<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nick Coleman</title>
    <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nick Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright ©2020 Nick Coleman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.nickcoleman.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Completed Finally</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed-finally/</guid>
      <description>The only thing left with the blog was to add a commenting system. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s default is Disqus, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want that for the usual reasons of lack-of-privacy and bloat. After searching around, I looked at isso and commento.
Commento needs Postgres whereas isso uses the much lighter SQLite. Since I get only a few comments, it&amp;rsquo;s isso first up.
The first obstacle is that the pip install fails immediately with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Good Day Out</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/a-good-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:43:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/a-good-day-out/</guid>
      <description>Every Sunday, the BMW Motorcycle Club of WA meets for morning coffee at Catalano&amp;rsquo;s cafe in Vic Park to talk about motorcycles and life. Around 8:30am, a group will form up behind the leader and head out for a nice ride to lunch in the countryside, doing a few hundred kilometres and away for several hours. It&amp;rsquo;s almost always a top ride and today was no exception.
Up to Lesmurdie and through the hills then down to the plain and a stint on the freeway to Kwinana then Rockingham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Not Complete</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-not-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-not-complete/</guid>
      <description>Setup is not complete, it turns out. I had been using the preview server to view my changes and everything looked fine as in my last post. But when I went to deploy the content over to the live server, I could not get the deployment to work. Most of the styling was missing and the site looked like a brutal minimalist site[1].
I spent an entire afternoon working on it with Github, Gitlab and Netlify, but with no success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Complete</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed/</guid>
      <description>I switched to the zola static site generator from hugo. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s theming seems complex and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a theme I liked, whereas I found one with zola almost immediately.
The blog setup using zola is pretty much complete. I&amp;rsquo;ve done an About, Contact Me and Search pages. The only thing left to do is a commenting system, but in the meantime, while I&amp;rsquo;m sorting that out, readers can get in touch via Contact Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Out</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/starting-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 23:10:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/starting-out/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started blogging after a six year break.
This is a new blog using the Hugo static website generator written in Go. It&amp;rsquo;s super fast at creating the site, less than 1 second.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go &amp;lt;ahem&amp;gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s some dummy content to test things out.
Test highlighting with some code examples:
Bash if i &amp;lt; 10; then i = 10 fi Looks good apart from the closing fi. I had to change the markdown from two tabs to eight spaces for i = 10 though, otherwise the indentation wasn&amp;rsquo;t recognised as markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix laptop frequency governor on resume after suspend</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/how-to-fix-laptop-frequency-governor-on-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/how-to-fix-laptop-frequency-governor-on-resume/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
If you are using Linux and the pm-utils suite from freedesktop.org to manage resume/suspend, and the chances are you are since most distros use it, then you could benefit from reading a recent post on my other blog [1].
Pm-utils’ implementation on CPU governor and CPU frequency is broken. If you use the userspace governor with a custom frequency, the frequency does not get restored on resume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Hot Hot</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/hot-hot-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/hot-hot-hot/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
Hot, hot, hot. The weather has been unbelievably hot for the last few days, with the same forecast for the next week.
Above is a screenshot from part of my status bar, showing 42°C (107°F), on Australia Day, 26th January 2012, at 3:00pm.
It shows the current temperature, “feels like” temperature, humidity, and wind direction and speed with gusts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tcpdump Light-weight Alternative to Wireshark</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/tcpdump-light-weight-alternative-to-wireshark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/tcpdump-light-weight-alternative-to-wireshark/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
I went to install Wireshark this morning and realised why I hadn’t bothered before. The source code is 20MB [^footnote]. God knows how long that will take to compile, especially since it seems to use autoconf and generates complex, multi-nested Makefiles many levels deep.
I already had tcpdump installed, so I used that instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calcc, A Programmers’ Calculator</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/calcc-a-programmers-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/calcc-a-programmers-calculator/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
I have been looking for a command-line programmers’ calculator for a while. I needed it to do the usual things like base number conversion, bit shifting and masking, and so on.
I searched for quite a while and couldn’t find anything. Almost all were GUI, which I didn’t want, or were some ridiculous price, which I couldn’t justify being a programmer myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vi Developed for Slow 300 baud Connections</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/vi-developed-for-slow-300-baud-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/vi-developed-for-slow-300-baud-connections/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
Interesting discussion on Hacker News about an interview with Bill Joy, creator of Vi.
Joy mentions that one of the most important use cases was that, in those days, everyone had only a 300 baud connection to the host. That meant the editor had to be efficient in screen repaints while interacting with commands from the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highest Australian Scores in Test Cricket</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/highest-australian-scores-in-test-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2012/highest-australian-scores-in-test-cricket/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
With India playing Australia at Sydney right now, and captain Michael Clarke on 325, I thought it would be interesting to look at the top ten Australian scores of all time (which Channel Nine has conveniently provided for us viewers). Matthew Hayden is highest at 380, then Don Bradman at 334 (Leeds in 1930).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2011/rails-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2011/rails-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>This is a lost post from my early blogs around 2012, rediscovered and posted here in mid-2020
Spent the last day or two doing Michael Hartl’s excellent Ruby on Rails tutorial.
I had a vague idea I wanted to learn Ruby, but once I googled for tutorials it became pretty clear that Rails was the way to go for web-based apps. Michael’s tutorial got lots of recommendations, so I jumped right in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
