<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 on Nick Coleman</title>
    <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/archives/2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 on Nick Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright ©2020 Nick Coleman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.nickcoleman.org/archives/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Completed Finally</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed-finally/</guid>
      <description>The only thing left with the blog was to add a commenting system. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s default is Disqus, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want that for the usual reasons of lack-of-privacy and bloat. After searching around, I looked at isso and commento.
Commento needs Postgres whereas isso uses the much lighter SQLite. Since I get only a few comments, it&amp;rsquo;s isso first up.
The first obstacle is that the pip install succeeds, but isso run fails immediately with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Good Day Out</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/a-good-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:43:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/a-good-day-out/</guid>
      <description>Every Sunday, the BMW Motorcycle Club of WA meets for morning coffee at Catalano&amp;rsquo;s cafe in Vic Park to talk about motorcycles and life. Around 8:30am, a group will form up behind the leader and head out for a nice ride to lunch in the countryside, doing a few hundred kilometres and away for several hours. It&amp;rsquo;s almost always a top ride and today was no exception.
Up to Lesmurdie and through the hills then down to the plain and a stint on the freeway to Kwinana then Rockingham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Not Complete</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-not-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-not-complete/</guid>
      <description>Setup is not complete, it turns out. I had been using the preview server to view my changes and everything looked fine as in my last post. But when I went to deploy the content over to the live server, I could not get the deployment to work. Most of the styling was missing and the site looked like a brutal minimalist site[1].
I spent an entire afternoon working on it with Github, Gitlab and Netlify, but with no success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Setup Complete</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/blog-setup-completed/</guid>
      <description>I switched to the zola static site generator from hugo. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s theming seems complex and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a theme I liked, whereas I found one with zola almost immediately.
The blog setup using zola is pretty much complete. I&amp;rsquo;ve done an About, Contact Me and Search pages. The only thing left to do is a commenting system, but in the meantime, while I&amp;rsquo;m sorting that out, readers can get in touch via Contact Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Out</title>
      <link>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/starting-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 23:10:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nickcoleman.org/2020/starting-out/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started blogging after a six year break.
This is a new blog using the Hugo static website generator written in Go. It&amp;rsquo;s super fast at creating the site, less than 1 second.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go &amp;lt;ahem&amp;gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s some dummy content to test things out.
Test highlighting with some code examples:
Bash if i &amp;lt; 10; then i = 10 fi Looks good apart from the closing fi. I had to change the markdown from two tabs to eight spaces for i = 10 though, otherwise the indentation wasn&amp;rsquo;t recognised as markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
